llbean.com 2017-10-11

# L.L.Bean: Your Privacy Rights

Your Privacy Rights

We appreciate the trust you place in L.L.Bean, and we are committed to respecting your privacy and the security of your personal information. Our privacy policy, updated on November 1, 2016, describes the information we collect and how we use it.

We always welcome your questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us at:

L.L.Bean, Dept. CFM  
Freeport, ME 04033  
Phone from US: 800-559-0747, ext. 58138  
Phone from outside US: (Access Code) + 207-552-3028  
Fax: 207-552-3080  
Email: preferences@llbean.com  

**Contents**

**Information We Collect**

We may collect information (including name, address, telephone number, email address, device location, transaction information, credit card information and date of birth) when you:

  * Place an order from our catalogs or on our website
  * Make a purchase at one of our stores (we do not require personal information, such as zip, name, address or email, as a condition of accepting payment by credit or debit card)
  * Checking and reserving store inventory on our website
  * Return an item or make an exchange
  * Inquire about our services
  * Request a catalog
  * Receive a gift package 
  * Create an account at llbean.com
  * Sign up for L.L.Bean email updates
  * Register for an Outdoor Discovery Schools® adventure
  * Enter a contest or sweepstakes
  * Are referred to us through a marketing promotion
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event
  * Maintain an L.L.Bean Visa Card account

We maintain the data that you provide us, along with a record of your purchases, in a secure database. To best serve you, we may combine this information with data that is publicly available and data that we receive from other reputable sources, including our credit card issuer, Barclays Bank Delaware, whose policies meet the Direct Marketing Association's privacy standards.

Our website also uses third-party analytics vendors such as Google Analytics. Please click here for more information about how data is collected and processed in connection with the Google Analytics service: [www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/). We and our third-party vendors or partners use analytics data for a variety of purposes such as to improve the design and content of our websites, to help us learn things like what pages are most attractive to all of our visitors and what promotions visitors like to see, and to gauge the success of our advertising campaigns.

We also gather information about how visitors navigate through our website by using clickstream data gathered with "cookies" and other online tools such as "pixel tags." See Cookies and Pixel Tags for further information.

 return to top

**Using Information We Collect**  
At L.L.Bean, we always want to provide you with the best possible shopping experience and fulfill your orders exactly as you've requested. To do this, we collect information that allows us to:

  * Process and track your order
  * Provide the services you request
  * Contact you about the status of an order
  * Send you catalogs or promotional offers we believe will be of interest to you
  * Send you L.L.Bean email updates
  * Identify your product and service preferences
  * Customize our communications to you
  * Provide information concerning product recalls or products you have purchased
  * Improve our merchandise selection and customer service

 return to top

**Information We Share with Others and Your Privacy Rights**  
We contract with other companies to provide certain services, including shipping, name and address verification, email distribution, market research, third party advertising, promotions management and payment processing (to view PayPal's privacy policy, please visit <https://www.paypal.com/privacy>). We provide these companies with only the information they need to perform their services and work closely with them to ensure that your privacy is respected and protected. These companies are prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than L.L.Bean.

From time to time, we make our mailing list (names and addresses only) and general shopping activity available to reputable companies whose products or services we believe will be of interest to you and whose privacy practices meet the Direct Marketing Association's privacy standards. We do not share email addresses for this purpose. If you do not want to receive mailings from other reputable companies and prefer that we do not share any information with these companies, please contact us.

If you apply for the L.L.Bean Visa Card, you provide the financial and personal information needed to process your application directly to Barclays Bank Delaware, the issuer and the administrator of the credit card program. Barclays Bank Delaware is independent of L.L.Bean and has its own privacy and security policies. You can review their policies at [_www.barclaycardus.com_](http://www.barclaycardus.com/).

On rare occasions, we may disclose specific information upon governmental request, in response to a court order, or when required by law to do so. We may also share information with companies assisting in fraud protection or investigation. We do not provide information to these agencies or companies for marketing or commercial purposes.

 return to top

**Your Choices about Communication from L.L.Bean**  
We offer choices about the types of information you receive from us. If you prefer not to receive catalogs or email updates from L.L.Bean or if you prefer to receive them less frequently, please visit the My Account section of llbean.com or contact us at the address shown below. You can also unsubscribe from our email updates using the link provided in each edition of the email.

If you do not wish to receive other communications from us, such as surveys, please contact us at:

L.L.Bean, Dept. CFM  
Freeport, ME 04033  
800-559-0747, ext. 58138  

So that we can be sure to identify you correctly, please be sure to provide us your exact name and address, or the mailing label from your catalog. Because mailings are planned in advance, it may take several weeks for your request to become effective. If due to human error you continue to receive unwanted communications, please contact us again, and we will make every effort to correct the situation.

To opt-out of direct personalized advertising on the Internet from L.L.Bean, click here.

**Third Party Catalog Opt-Out Services**

Many third-party services are available to help you opt out of catalog mailings. After careful consideration of customer service, data protection, privacy and fees, L.L.Bean no longer honors requests made by these organizations. We do not think you should have to pay third parties to opt out of catalog mailings. We prefer to hear from you directly so we can best meet your needs—we want you to be satisfied with the communications you receive and are happy to honor your preference requests. Contacting us is easy; please refer to **Your Choices About Communication from L.L.Bean** in the section above.

 return to top

**Cookies and Pixel Tags**  
A cookie is a small data file stored by your Web browser on your computer. Cookies enable you to place an order on our website. They also allow us to enhance and personalize your online shopping experience, so the information you receive is more relevant to you.

For example, we use cookies to:

  * Remember what items are in your Shopping Bag
  * Recognize you when you return to our website
  * Enables faster checkout, if you have created an account at llbean.com
  * Study how our customers navigate through our website and which products they request in site searches
  * Deliver personalized marketing from L.L.Bean

If you set your browser to refuse cookies, please call us at 800-221-4221 to place your order.

We also use pixel tags – tiny graphic images – to tell us what parts of our website you have visited or to measure the effectiveness of any searches you may do on our site. Pixel tags also enable us to send you email in a format you can read and let us know when you have opened an email message from us.

We may also contract with other companies who use cookies or other online tools such as pixel tags to measure the performance of a marketing effort on our behalf. We prohibit these companies from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than L.L.Bean.

We also contract with third party advertising companies to serve ads on our behalf across the Internet. To do this, they will collect anonymous information about your visits to our website and your interaction with our products and services. They may also use information about your visits to this and other websites to target advertisements. These targeted advertisements may appear on other sites that you visit. This anonymous information is collected through the use of a cookie or pixel tag – industry standard technology used by most major websites. No personally identifiable information is collected in this process. To opt-out of this type of messaging, please click here.

 return to top

**How We Use Email**  
When you provide us your email address, we will email you as necessary to process your order, respond to a request or provide customer service. For example, after you place an order at llbean.com, you will receive an email confirmation and, in most cases, an email with package tracking information. Recipients of our email gift cards will receive an email notifying them of the gift and instructing them how to redeem it.

We may also send promotional emails about products, special offers, services or events we believe may be of interest to you. It is our intent to send promotional emails only to those who wish to receive them. We provide instructions on how to unsubscribe in each email and within the [My Account](https://www.llbean.com/webapp/wcs/stores/servlet/ShowCustPref?storeId=1&nav=gn&langId=-1) section of llbean.com.

 return to top

**Direct to Business Preferences**  
Please note that the [My Account](https://www.llbeanbusiness.com/llbean/login) section of our Direct to Business website, located at llbeanbusiness.com, is not designed to change catalog mailing and email preferences. If you prefer not to receive Direct to Business catalogs or email updates please contact us at:

L.L.Bean, Dept. CFM  
Freeport, ME 04033  
800-559-0747, ext. 58138  

 return to top

**Links to Other Sites**  
Occasionally we provide links on our website to other sites to enhance the functionality and shopping experience. These sites operate independently of L.L.Bean and have established their own privacy and security policies. For the best online experience, we strongly encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit.

 return to top

**Updating or Reviewing Your Information**  
To update your customer information (name, address, telephone number and email address), please contact us at the address above. A limited amount of purchase information may also be available to you. To protect your privacy, we will need to validate your identity before you update or review your information.

 return to top

**Security**  
It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you or received from a partner. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of our customer data. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract to only what they need to carry out their responsibilities. It is our practice to use encryption whenever we receive or transmit sensitive data.

When you make a purchase, request a catalog or create an account on our website, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format. See About Security for details.

 return to top

**Privacy of Children on Our website**  
Our website is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13.

 return to top

**Policy Changes**  
From time to time, we may use customer information for unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change, we will post these changes on our website. We encourage you to review our privacy policy periodically.

 return to top

**Quality Assurance for Customer Service Interactions**  
To make sure we continue to offer the best service possible, your communication with Customer Service may be monitored for quality assurance.

 return to top

**Questions or Comments?**  
For questions, comments or assistance, we invite you to contact us.

We hope to answer any questions to your satisfaction, but should you ever want to contact a third party regarding our privacy practices, you can email the Direct Marketing Association's Committee on Ethical Business Practices at [ethics@the-dma.org](mailto:ethics@the-dma.org). The DMA is the oldest and largest association for consumers and companies with interest in direct marketing.

 return to top
